

817.709.4331

■ donia.blair@gmail.com

• Fort Worth, TX

SUMMARY

I am a detail-driven digital architect focused on building high-performing WordPress websites that elevate user experience and drive business growth. From refining site speed and server performance to analyzing user behavior with Microsoft Clarity, I ensure every site is optimized for reliability and engagement. I work closely with clients and internal teams to maintain, improve, and secure digital platforms that are not just functional-but built to last.

EXPERIENCE

2024 - Present

Lasso Up

Lead WordPress Developer

Build, optimize, and maintain WordPress websites in modern page builders, analyze user behavior with Microsoft Clarity, oversee server monitoring and maintenance, coordinate with external vendors to manage tasks and ensure ongoing functionality.

2015 - 2023

Ride For The Brand

Web Developer/Senior Web Developer

Created custom WordPress themes and templates based on design comps using HTML5, SCSS, jQuery, and PHP.

2013 - 2015

Acosta Sales & Marketing

Retail Auditor/Merchandiser

Established corporate relationships, collected store level information, maintained product continuity, built and stocked product displays.

EDUCATION

2012 - 2015

Web Design & Interactive Media

The Art Institute of Fort Worth

Bachelor of Fine Arts

2010 - 2012

Graphic Design

Texas Christian University

54 completed credits

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5 • CSS3/SCSS • Bootstrap
Flexbox • CSS Grid • JavaScript
jQuery • AJAX • PHP • WordPress
Elementor • Divi • WooCommerce
Core Web Vitals • Microsoft Clarity
DNS • SSL • Basic Server
Monitoring & Hosting Management

Exposure To:

React • Angular • Command Line Headless WordPress • GraphQL Shopify

CONNECT



www.linkedin.com/in/doniablair

References available upon request.

"If you are working on something that you really care about, you don't have to be pushed. The vision pulls you."

STEVE JOBS